Blake Rochelle

UXC UX/UI Designer

Contact

Address

Gulf Breeze, FL 32563

Phone

2564041521

E-mail

blakerochelle@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/blakerochelle/

www

https://blakerochelle.github.io/

Skills

User Centered Design

Excellent

Iterative Design

Excellent

Responsive Design and Development

Excellent

User Interface (UI) Design

Very Good

UI Prototyping

Very Good

HTML SCSS Javascript JQuery

Highly skilled UX/UI designer and developer with over 15 years of experience in User Centered Design and web functionality integration as well as experience conducting various methods of user research and producing interactive product application interface prototypes.

Maintains user-centric design principles while adhering to related development goals and business requirements. Dedicated to creating inviting and delightful interfaces for a variety of complex proprietary systems.

Work History

2021-10 -Current

UX/UI Designer

Jackson Hewitt, Gulf Breeze, United States

- Lead UX/UI designer for Jackson Hewitt's Tax Resolution Division
- Worked hand-in-hand with product owner and business liaison to translate business objectives and workflows into project feature requirements and polished user interfaces.
- Defined user experience of the JH Tax Resolution web application and provided workflow mockups, interactive prototypes and high-fidelity graphics using Figma for design and collaboration.
- Created user personas for all roles and conducted user interviews at each step of the way in order to gain empathy and a deep understanding of our users.
- Conducted user testing sessions in order to confirm or refute all design assumptions. All assumptions were tracked via Trello using feature-specific cards.
- Created living style guide for the Tax Resolution application and all extraneous web solutions.
- Integrated finalized design into the Tax Resolution web application via SCSS.

2010-09 -2021-10

UX Designer

Kemper Corporation, Previously Infinity Insurance, Birmingham, AL

- Lead UX designer for Infinity Insurance
- Promoted and ensured consistent look, feel and experience across multiple Kemper/Infinity domains

Excellent

and platforms.

- Defined user experience concepts and provided design layouts, workflows, prototypes and high-fidelity graphics using the Adobe suite and Sketch.
- Created and maintained libraries of reusable web components.
- Closely collaborated with cross-functional teams and business units to turn requirements into completed apps, within project deadlines, and to identify and quickly address problems.
- Developed and facilitated UX workshops, to help promote optimum user experience across the organization, with 95% positive feedback from attendees.

2003-10 -2010-09

Lead Web Developer

Red Mountain Technologies, Birmingham, AL

- Utilized user-centric principals to design and develop web-based applications.
- Maintained existing applications to ensure their accuracy and currency.
- Performed technical support duties and customer interaction training.
- Served as project coordinator which included managing current project goals as well as long term team goals.
- Planned, designed and prepared company newsletter for digital and print dissemination.

2002-02 -2003-10

Customer Service Representative

AutoCheck Auctions, Birmingham, AL

- Vehicle history data provider to over 95% of the auction industry.
- Interacted one-on-one with customers to help serve their individual needs.
- Coordinated with management to strengthen relationships with our customers.
- Analyzed various data streams to determine the accuracy of historical vehicle information.

Education

1997-09 -20012 Bachelor of Science: Business Administration, Management Information

Systems

Auburn University - Auburn, AL

Certifications

2018-03 UX Certification, Nielsen Norman Group